## Ashwin Yardi

🗣 Pune, Maharashtra, India 🗷 ashwin@bitsbyblocks.com 🛘 08149265041 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashwin-yardi/ 📤 https://bitsbyblocks.com/

#### SUMMARY

7 years of experience developing and designing Web3 Dapps as a senior/lead developer with experience managing and leading teams. Comprehensive understanding of the industry as a result of gaining crucial experience as a cofounder and early team member for multiple projects. A history of accomplishment in overseeing product development and supervising engineering teams. Looking forward to utilise Web3, engineering, leadership, and product development expertise to help the talented teams and promising projects.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### CoFounder

#### **AuroBlocks Studios**

June 2022 - Present, Remote

- · Responsible for devising technical solutions, architecture, and development plans for different projects to ensure they met client requirements and were sustainable long-term.
- · Led the entire services agency, including marketing, lead generation, client communication, and project management.
- · Created processes and development guidelines to ensure efficient and effective project management.
- · Handled project deliverables, ensuring they met client requirements and were delivered on time and on budget.
- Managed a team of developers, providing guidance and technical direction.
- · Active involvement in the coding and development side of projects.
- Ensured documentation was completed accurately and on time.
- · Prioritized client satisfaction through clear communication and expectation management.

# CoFounder and CTO

**Cryption Network** 

May 2021 - May 2023, Remote

- Designed and built the Polydex DEX and in-house DEX aggregator from scratch.
- · Led the development of DappFactory, a smart contract as a service platform that was later used by projects like Quickswap and a few others.
- · Built functional smart contracts from scratch, including Fixed APR staking contracts and NFT staking contracts, on the DappFactory platform.
- · Benchmarked existing smart contracts to identify inefficiencies and proposed optimizations for improved performance of the platform.
- · Developed the Cryption Mobile Wallet to provide an easy-to-use mobile experience for users to access their crypto assets.
- · Implemented improvements on top of the Conditional tokens used by the Seer prediction market, resulting in a customized solution with added value.
- · Utilized Solidity, Typescript, and Python to deploy multiple full-fledged DeFi protocols to ensure various blockchains interoperability.
- · Led a team of developers to facilitate requirements gathering, architect solutions, and execute the delivery of high-quality products.
- · Coordinated with the executive team to develop and implement a long-term strategic vision for strengthening Cryption's market position.
- · Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure smooth project flow and maintain efficient communication channels.
- · Documented all technical details and created comprehensive guidelines to ensure smooth maintenance and scalability of platforms.

#### **Full Stack Blockchain Engineer** Fetch.ai

November 2020 - May 2021, Remote

- · Built multiple smart contracts for the Mettalex platform, including a yield farming contract with features such as single-sided liquidity that drove the MTLX token price to \$10.
- · Developed a backend service for locating autonomous agents, creating an improved user experience.
- · Created smart contracts for Mettalex's Phoenix program, enabling FET token staking to earn additional rewards in MTLX tokens.
- · Participated in exclusive strategic discussions with CEO of Fetch.ai.
- · Forked and evaluated the idle finance protocol.

# **Principle Engineer**

August 2020 - May 2021, Remote

- · Single handedly developed the entire MVP of the platform, which led to successful fundraising of over \$4 million for the project.
- · Developed the base smart contracts and backend for the StackOS platform, allowing over 1,500 dapps to deploy through the backend.
- · Oversaw the development process and provided technical guidance to the team, resulting in high-quality code.
- · Collaborated with stakeholders to develop long-term strategies for improving platform functionality and fostering growth.

## **Solution Engineer**

Deqode

## July 2017 - October 2020, Pune, India

- · As a lead developer, architected and implemented end to end blockchain solutions for clients using Agile development methodologies.
- · Developed a Chrome extension wallet plugin that provides a secure identity vault and an interface to manage Ethereum identities.
- · Developed smart contracts to facilitate ICOs and token distributions
- · Decentralized storage systems, Identity management; cross-border currency exchanges; Asset lending platforms.
- · Worked on backends with Microservices architecture, Docker, Kubernetes, and Nest.js
- · Hands-on experience with Ethereum development and ecosystem (smart contracts, truffle, wallets, exchanges, metamask)
- · Developed a blockchain explorer for public blockchains like Bitcoin and Ethereum using a fast and robust queue-based architecture for concurrent job processing.
- · Responsible for leading the development and maintenance efforts for multiple Node/Typescript based DAPP backends.
- · Part of the training team, involved in planning and executing training programs for freshers and laterals.

## PERSONAL BLOG

## BitsByBlocks - A technical blog related to Web3 development

BitsByBlocks · January 2022 - Present

- · Started writing the blog on my personal website related to web3 development, solidity, smart contracts, and other stuff.
- · Gained popularity with around 10,000 monthly impressions and 300 unique clicks.
- · Wrote an ebook about the "Ethereum Proof of Stake" consensus algorithm.

## **EDUCATION**

## Post Graduate Certification in Blockchain Technology

International Institute of Information Technology Bangalore · Banglore, India · 2020

## **Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering**

Pune Institute of Computer Technology · Pune, India · 2017

## **SKILLS**

Solidity, TypeScript, Nest.js, React.js, Python, Architecture, GraphQL, Communication, Documentation, Content creation, Research, Strategy, Leadership